photoawards.com 2019-07-11

# Privacy Policy - International Photography Awards™

### **Important Notice!**

This is an important notice regarding your privacy and the way in which International Photography Awards (IPA) (referred to as “we”, “our” or “us” in this policy) collects and makes use of your personal data. We want to be open and transparent with you, and therefore encourage you to contact us if you have any questions about this policy or the ways in which we use your personal data.

This policy applies to our subscribers, Awards applicants and business contacts generally. We take our privacy responsibilities seriously and are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy.

###  **Privacy Policy**

The **International Photography Awards (IPA)** respects personal identity and information by promoting the use of fair information practices. This privacy statement covers the site https://www.photoawards.com/

 **International Photography Awards (IPA)** is the sole owner of any information collected on https://www.photoawards.com/

###  **Information collection**

 **International Photography Awards (IPA)** respects collect information from users at multiple points on its web site. We only collect information that is essential to serve you, present your work to the jury, inform you of your winning, remind you of deadlines or to promote your winning, your company and your work to the public.

Any personal information collected in forms is for our private use only. Phone numbers, mail address, and email addresses will not be sold or distributed to third parties or published online.

###  **Information you provide to us**

For example, we collect information when you register with **International Photography Awards (IPA)** respects for an account, or create a new submission, request costumer support, or leave us a testimonial.

The type of information we collect directly from you include your name, email, company name, address, position, and other contact information. We also require information about your project that is being submitted into the **International Photography Awards (IPA)** respects award program.

This includes:

  * Name of photography and/or series
  * Photographer name
  * Company Name
  * Email address
  * Etc…

###  **Information collected by Cookies, web analytics and tracking technologies:  **

We may use technologies that save cookies to your computer or mobile device. Cookies are small data files stored on your hard drive or in device memory that help us to improve your experience on the **International Photography Awards (IPA)** respects website. Cookies are only to understand our advertising performance with minimal information collected. We will not follow and record your activity once you leave our website. We may also collect information using web analytics services. These services, such as Google Analytics help us understand how to improve visitor experience on the website.

###  **Where we store your personal information**

Electronic versions of your personal information are stored on our supplier platform located in the US and India.

The servers which we use to provide our services to you depends on the location that you or your organization is based; to make it user friendly and faster. For example, if you or your organization elects for our services to be provided within Europe, then the server used to provide our service to you or your organization will be based within Europe.

Where we use third party service providers to assist us, your personal information may also be stored in accordance with their practices and procedures. We require third parties to respect your personal information and to treat it in accordance with the law.

###  **Use of Information**

The information may be used to perform a variety of purposes, including to:

  * Promote winners of the **International Photography Awards (IPA)** program,
  * Remind registrants of the upcoming deadlines,
  * Notify winners of their win,
  * Send updates, and news regarding **International Photography Awards (IPA)** and other Farmani Group related competitions, and select partners,
  * Respond, and help with customer service support questions,
  * Monitor and analyse trends, usage of marketing effectiveness,
  * Prevent illegal activities, spamming and other unauthorized usage of the **International Photography Awards (IPA)** website,
  * Present relevant advertising to visitors.

###  **Rights to  access, erase and be forgotten **

**Your rights in connection with your personal information**

  * Request access to your personal information (commonly known as a “data subject access request”). This enables you to receive a copy of your personal information and to check we are lawfully processing it.
  * Request correction of your personal information. This enables you to have any incomplete or inaccurate personal information corrected.
  * Request the erasure of your personal information. This enables you to ask us to delete or remove personal information where there is no good reason for us continuing to process it. You also have the right to ask us to stop processing personal information where we are relying on a legitimate interest and there is something about your particular situation which makes you want to object to processing on this ground.
  * Request to be forgotten; we will delete all your personal data from our servers.

If you want to review, verify, correct or request erasure of your personal information, object to the processing of your personal information, or request that we transfer a copy of your personal information to another party, please contact us at support@photoawards.com

###  **What we may need from you**

We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access the information (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is a security measure to ensure that personal information is not disclosed to another person who has no right to receive it.

###  **Right to withdraw consent**

In the limited circumstances where you may have provided your consent to the collecting, processing and transfer of your personal information for a specific purpose, you have the right to withdraw your consent for that specific processing at any time. To withdraw your consent, please contact us at support@photoawards.com

Where we are providing you with marketing information, you can also change your marketing preferences by using the unsubscribe button at the bottom of our marketing e-mails to you.

Once we have received notification that you have withdrawn your consent, we will no longer process your personal information for the purpose or purposes you originally agreed to, unless we have another legitimate basis for doing so.

###  **Sharing and Disclosure of Information**

To promote our winners, we share information about their projects with media, partners, and in press releases. We will not share any of your personal information, or information that is not intended for publicity. We require third parties and partners to respect the security of your personal information and to treat it in accordance with the law.

###  **Opting Out of  ** **Newsletter Communications**

You may opt out of receiving reminder and newsletter emails from **International Photography Awards (IPA)** by following the opt-out instructions provided in those emails. You may also opt-out of receiving promotional emails and other promotional communications from us at any time by emailing the **International Photography Awards (IPA)** support team with your specific request. If you opt out from the newsletters, we may still send you non-promotional communications, such as notifications of your winning or other important information that benefits you, but this may be affected if you unsubscribed from the **International Photography Awards (IPA)** list.

###  **Cookies**

Most web browsers are set to accept cookies by default. If you would like, you can usually choose to set your browser to remove or reject browser cookies or to prompt you before accepting such a cookie. Please note that, if you choose to remove or reject browser cookies, this could affect the availability or functionality of **International Photography Awards (IPA)** website.

###  **Testimonials**

We display personal testimonials of happy winners on our website. With your consent we may post your testimonial along with your name and use these testimonials to provide you with even more publicity and exposure.

###  **Links**

This website contains links to other sites. Please be aware that **International Photography Awards (IPA)** is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. **International Photography Awards (IPA)** encourages our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this web site.

###  **Payment Security**

This website uses 256-bit SSL encryption and all payment are processed by Stripe or Paypal. **International Photography Awards (IPA)** does not have direct access or store credit card information.

 **If you have any questions please don’t hesitate to contact us at** support@photoawards.com
